Finding Aid for Scott Chaplin collection, 1966-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Scott Chaplin collection 1966-1989, 1969-1986
Chaplin, Scott, collector.
1 linear feet
9437 Aa 2
1986 graduate of the University of Michigan, member of the Ann Arbor-Managua Initiative for Soil Testing Development brigade. Topical files concerning student/community organizations and student academic programs, including the Humanitarian Assistance Project for the Independent Development of Agriculture in Nicaragua, the University of Michigan Committee on the Underclass Experience, the University of Michigan Residential College, and the Ann Arbor-Managua Initiative for Soil Testing Development brigade.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were donated by Scott Chaplin (donor no. 8262 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Scott Chaplin, a 1986 graduate of the University of Michigan and a native of Kalamazoo, Michigan, was a member of the Ann Arbor-Managua Initiative for Soil Testing Development (A2Mistad) brigade.
The Scott Chaplin papers document various student related organizations in the university community. The records span the years 1966-1989, with the bulk of the materials covering 1969-1986. The papers are divided into two series: Topical Files and Photographs.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor-Managua Initiative for Soil Testing Development.; Humanitarian Assistance Project for Independent Agricultural Development in Nicaragua (U.S.); Nicaragua.; University of Michigan. Committee on the Underclass Experience.; University of Michigan. Residential College.; University of Michigan--Students.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Humanitarian Assistance Project for Independent Agricultural Development in Nicaragua (U.S.); Nicaragua.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files (1 liner foot) consist of an alphabetical run of files relating to student/community organizations and student academic programs. Included among the papers are files of HAP-NICA (Humanitarian Assistance Project for the Independent Development of Agriculture in Nicaragua), and documents about the University of Michigan's Committee on the Underclass Experience (CUE) and the University of Michigan's Residential College.
  Hap-Nica was a project of the New World Agriculture Group and the Guild House Campus Ministry in Ann Arbor. Hap-Nica worked in conjunction with farm workers, unions and the Higher Institute of Agricultural Science in Nicaragua to promote the development of Nicaragua's capacity to raise its own food. Hap-Nica provided financial and technical assistance. The Hap-Nica newsletters document the projects and interests of the organization. Included within the files are the records of A2Mistad, a brigade that assisted in the construction of a soil testing laboratory in Managua, Nicaragua, to house equipment donated by the Italian government. The records include meeting minutes and fund raising information. Seeds of Hope, an eighteen-minute slide show documentary produced by Hap-Nica is also included within the files. The documentary includes slides, text and audio cassette recording.
  The University of Michigan Committee on the Underclass Experience (CUE) originated in 1970. The committee, comprised of students and faculty, was concerned with improving the quality of teaching through grants, the appointment of departmental associates, an informal newsletter, seminars, workshops, and continuing education initiatives. The "General" folder contains information describing the fundamentals of the program.
  - Humanitarian Assistance Project for the Independent Development of Agriculture in Nicaragua (Hap-Nica)
    - General 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - A2Mistad
      - General 1986-1989 (Box 1)
      - Managua, Nicaragua
        - General 1986 (Box 1)
        - Meeting Notes
          - 1987 (Box 1)
          - 1989 (Box 1)
      - Meeting Minutes
        - 1986 (Box 1)
        - 1987 (Box 1)
        - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
      - Publicity 1985-1987 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter 1985-1987 (Box 1)
    - Seeds of Hope, 1982 (Box 1)
      (presentation, includes script, slides, and cassette audio tape)
  - North Campus Fraternity Park undated (proposal) (Box 1)
  - People's Action Coalition (PAC)
    - General 1978 (Box 1)
    - Education Conference 1978 (Box 1)
    - Events 1978 (Box 1)
    - Meeting Agendas and Minutes 1979 (Box 1)
    - Student Government Committee 1979 (Box 1)
  - Program for Educational and Social Change (PESC)
    - General 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Education Conference 1974 (Box 1)
    - State of the University Debate Series 1972 (Box 1)
  - Samoff Student Support Committee 1978-1980 (re: tenure) (Box 1)
  - School and College Government Task Force 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Student Bookstore Proposal 1969 (Box 1)
  - Student Conduct, Regulations Concerning 1969 (Box 1)
  - Student Government Council, College of Literature, Science and the Arts 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - Student Organizational Regulations undated (Box 1)
  - Student Participation in School and College Governance 1974 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Commission on the Role of Students in Decision Making 1966-1969 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Committee on the Underclass Experience (CUE)
    - General 1972 (Box 1)
    - Academic Quality 1970 (of entering freshmen) (Box 1)
    - Bachelor of General Studies 1969-1971 (Box 1)
    - Closed Courses 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Committee Minutes 1971-1972 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Freshman Experience 1970 (Box 1)
    - Grading Procedures 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Interim Report 1972 (Box 1)
    - Living Learning Project 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Modular Scheduling 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Pilot Program 1971 (Box 1)
    - Political Economy Program 1972 (Box 1)
    - Project Listings undated (Box 1)
    - Proposals 1973 (Box 1)
    - Self-Paced Course undated (Box 1)
    - Start Your Own Course undated (Box 1)
    - Survey 1971 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Residential College
    - General 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Reports
      - Reactions of Residential College Faculty to the College, the Students, and the Core Curriculum, 1970 (Box 1)
      - A Small Residential College Compared with Three Control Populations, undated (Box 1)
      - Student Comments on the Core Curriculum and the Residential College 1969-1970, undated (Box 1)
      - The University of Michigan's Residential College, 1971 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - A2Mistad 1986-1989, b&w and color photographs from Managua construction brigade, 2 b&w of Bach School presentation (Box 1)